hey guys somebody sent me this request
and I kind of like it it looks like a
fun one and I was a little bit curious
how I would visualize this so I'm going
to pull them out of here so we have the
red bar and the green bar and then we
also have this purple wall these are the
Shadows that they're making and we're
given all of these measurements the
green box is 2 m high with the shadow of
three along the ground this Shadow
measures 6 M and up the wall it measures
4 M now we're trying to solve for the
height of the red bar so let's call that
X we don't need most of this wall let's
smush it down and we can imagine if the
wall was isn't there the shadow would go
about this far but we don't know how far
this is so let's give it a variable y
let's focus on this part and this part
right here we can set up a proportion we
can say that 2 over 3 is equal to 4 over
y because the Shadows are proportional
to the heights of the objects and now to
solve for y we can cross multiply 2 * y
will give us 2 Y and that's going to be
equal to 3 * 4 which is 12 and then we
can divide both sides by two and we get
Y is equal to 6 so we can update this y
to be 6 M we know from here to here the
shadow is 6 M and then from here to here
it's 6 M the whole thing is going to be
12 M so now we no longer need this thing
and we can set up another proportion the
2 over 3 will equal x over 12 and now to
solve for x we're going to cross
multiply 3 * X is 3x and that's going to
be equal to 2 * 12 which is 24 and then
we can divide both sides by 3 and we get
x = 24 over 3 which is 8 x was the
height of our red bar so we can change
this to 8 m and now we're done that's
the answer to our question let's put a
box around it how exciting